{
    "current_affairs": [
        {
            "date": "5th Feb 2022",
            "affairs": [
                {
                    "Question": "",
                    "optionA": "",
                    "optionB": "",
                    "optionC": "",
                    "optionD": "",
                    "Answar": "",
                    "Title": "[India] Khijadiya wildlife sanctuary",
                    "solution": "Two new Ramsar sites were announced on the occasion of World Wetlands Day. They are: Khijadiya wildlife sanctuary in Gujarat and Bakhira wildlife sanctuary in Uttar Pradesh. India has a network of 49 such sites covering 10,93,636 hectares, which is the highest in South Asia. The Union Environment Ministry had earlier notified the Sultanpur National Park and Bhindawas wildlife sanctuary in Jhajjar as Ramsar sites in Haryana.",
                    "keyString": "a000000r2",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                },
                {
                    "Question": "",
                    "optionA": "",
                    "optionB": "",
                    "optionC": "",
                    "optionD": "",
                    "Answar": "",
                    "Title": "Super Hornet fighter aircraft",
                    "solution": "The marine version of the French-made Rafale fighter jet has been successfully flight-tested at a shore-based facility in Goa. The Rafale-M competes against the US-made Super Hornet, as both of which are being evaluated for a purchase by the Indian Navy for deployment on INS Vikrant. It is a 44,000-tonne indigenously developed aircraft carrier, that is undergoing trials for commissioning in August.",
                    "keyString": "a000000r3",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                },
                {
                    "Question": "",
                    "optionA": "",
                    "optionB": "",
                    "optionC": "",
                    "optionD": "",
                    "Answar": "",
                    "Title": "[India] One Nation One Ration Card",
                    "solution": "Chhattisgarh has recently implemented ‘One Nation One Ration Card’ (ONORC) plan, under which the people of the state can lift their food-grains quota from any ration shops across the country. With the integration of Chhattisgarh, the ONORC plan is now operational in 35 States/UTs covering almost 96.8 per cent of about 77 crore NFSA beneficiaries in the country. This was announced by the Department of Food & Public Distribution.",
                    "keyString": "a000000r4",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                }
                ,
                {
                    "Question": "",
                    "optionA": "",
                    "optionB": "",
                    "optionC": "",
                    "optionD": "",
                    "Answar": "",
                    "Title": "Skeletal remains of a man buried near a headless horse",
                    "solution": "Researchers have recently found skeletal remains of a man buried near a headless horse. The remains have been found in Knittlingen in southern Germany.Researchers estimate that the man and the horse must have been buried 1400 years ago when the area was ruled by Merovingian dynasty.",
                    "keyString": "a000000r5",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                }
                
            ]
        },
        {
            "date": "4th Feb 2022",
            "affairs": [
                {
                    "Question": "",
                    "optionA": "",
                    "optionB": "",
                    "optionC": "",
                    "optionD": "",
                    "Answar": "",
                    "Title": "4th February World Cancer Day",
                    "solution": "Every year on 4 February World Cancer Day is observed globally and is celebrated by WHO to aware people of the disease Cancer and how to cure it. This year’s World Cancer Day will be observed on February 4th, with the theme “Close the Care Gap.” The three-year “Close the Care Gap” campaign of World Cancer Day was initially presented to participants on the Summit platform in the run-up to the World Cancer Leaders’ Summit.",
                    "keyString": "rttttt4554",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                },
                {
                    "Question": "",
                    "optionA": "",
                    "optionB": "",
                    "optionC": "",
                    "optionD": "",
                    "Answar": "",
                    "Title": "COMiT-Net",
                    "solution": "Researchers from the Indian Institute of Technology (IIT) Jodhpur have developed an Artificial Intelligence (AI)-based chest X-ray diagnosis technique using X-Ray that can detect COVID-19.The AI-based solution can be an alternative to the regular RT PCR tests conducted across the world. The Researchers from the institute proposed a deep learning-based algorithm, COMiT-Net, which can differentiate between a COVID-19 affected lung and a non-COVID affected lung.",
                    "keyString": "3434534",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                },
                {
                    "Question": "",
                    "optionA": "",
                    "optionB": "",
                    "optionC": "",
                    "optionD": "",
                    "Answar": "",
                    "Title": "ISIS leader Quraishi kills himself during Syria raid, U.S. says",
                    "solution": "Abu Ibrahim al-Hashemi al-Quraishi, had led Islamic State since the death in 2019 of its founder Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi, who was also killed when he detonated explosives during a raid by U.S. commandos.",
                    "keyString": "t4",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                },
                {
                    "Question": "",
                    "optionA": "",
                    "optionB": "",
                    "optionC": "",
                    "optionD": "",
                    "Answar": "",
                    "Title": "Which country inaugurated the Ijmuiden Sea Lock, the world’s largest sea lock?",
                    "solution": "The Netherlands.\nDutch King Willem-Alexander officially opened the Ijmuiden Sea Lock, which is claimed to be the largest sea lock in the world.\nThe 500-metre long and 70-metre-wide structure replaces a smaller 100-year-old one at Ijmuiden, a port city connecting the North Sea Canal to the port of Amsterdam. The structure is deep enough that ships will not have to wait for a favourable water level to enter the canal.",
                    "keyString": "t42134f",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                },
                {
                    "Question": "",
                    "optionA": "",
                    "optionB": "",
                    "optionC": "",
                    "optionD": "",
                    "Answar": "",
                    "Title": "Which state launched ‘Project Sadbhawana’ to improve Governance? [INDIA]",
                    "solution": "Assam\nAssam Chief Minister Himanta Biswa Sarma launched “Project Sadbhawana”. It aims to dispose over 4-5 lakh pending files lying in the State secretariat within a year.A portal will be created where people can inform of their pending files. Along with project Sadbhavana, a Swachhata Abhiyan in Janata Bhawan will also be launched to promote cleanliness in all the departments in the Secretariat.",
                    "keyString": "a00001",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                },
                {
                    "Question": "",
                    "optionA": "",
                    "optionB": "",
                    "optionC": "",
                    "optionD": "",
                    "Answar": "",
                    "Title": "When is the ‘World Neglected Tropical Diseases Day’ observed?",
                    "solution": "January 30\nWorld Neglected Tropical Diseases Day’ is observed on January 30 every year, to raise awareness on neglected tropical diseases. This year’s World NTD Day was commemorated under the theme ‘Achieving health equity to end the neglect of poverty-related diseases’. Some examples of NTDs are Chagas disease, Chikungunya, Dengue, Leprosy, Rabies and Trachoma among others. They affect 1 billion people globally..",
                    "keyString": "a00002",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                },
                {
                    "Question": "",
                    "optionA": "",
                    "optionB": "",
                    "optionC": "",
                    "optionD": "",
                    "Answar": "",
                    "Title": "‘Lake Albert’ is located as a border between which two countries?",
                    "solution": "Uganda and Democratic Republic of Congo.\nTwo Oil Giants- France’s TotalEnergies and the China National Offshore Oil Corporation (CNOOC) signed a USD 10 million deal to develop Uganda’s energy resources and build a Regional oil pipeline.The project aims to exploit the crude oil reserves at Lake Albert, a 160-kilometre natural border between Uganda and the Democratic Republic of Congo.",
                    "keyString": "a00003",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "date": "2nd Feb 2022",
            "affairs": [
                {
                    "Question": "",
                    "optionA": "",
                    "optionB": "",
                    "optionC": "",
                    "optionD": "",
                    "Answar": "",
                    "Title": "2nd February, World wetlands day",
                    "solution": "Every year on 2nd February, World Wetlands Day is celebrated internationally. This day marks the date of the adoption of the Convention on Wetlands on 2nd February, 1971, in Ramsar, Iran. It was first celebrated in 1997. Wetlands, often known as “liquid assets” are the of the most crucial natural resources that help stabilise water supplies, cleanse polluted waters, protect shorelines, and recharge groundwater aquifers.",
                    "keyString": "w4r1",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                },
                {
                    "Question": "",
                    "optionA": "",
                    "optionB": "",
                    "optionC": "",
                    "optionD": "",
                    "Answar": "",
                    "Title": "US blocks Pak ambassador Masood Khan's appointment. ",
                    "solution": "In a massive global embarrassment for Pakistan, the United States blocked the appointment of a new Pakistan ambassador due to possible terror links. Perry wrote a stinging letter to US President Joe Biden against Pakistan's decision calling Khan a terror sympathizer who praised terror organizations and terrorists like Hizbul Mujahideen and Burhan Wani.",
                    "keyString": "tyg45",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                },
                {
                    "Question": "",
                    "optionA": "",
                    "optionB": "",
                    "optionC": "",
                    "optionD": "",
                    "Answar": "",
                    "Title": "India, Russia hold consultations on UN",
                    "solution": "Russian Deputy Foreign Minister Sergey Vershinin held consultations with Reenat Sandhu, Secretary (West) in the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) here and exchanged views on typical issues of the UN Security Council work, including the situation in Afghanistan, Syria, Libya and Myanmar.",
                    "keyString": "35fdgfd",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                },
                {
                    "Question": "",
                    "optionA": "",
                    "optionB": "",
                    "optionC": "",
                    "optionD": "",
                    "Answar": "",
                    "Title": "Honduras's first woman president",
                    "solution": "Xiomara Castro has been sworn in as Honduras’ first female president, taking office amid growing uncertainty about whether she will be able to govern in the face of an unfolding legislative crisis and other challenges",
                    "keyString": "ertert",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "date": "25th Jan 2022",
            "affairs": [
                {
                    "Question": "“Yogyata” mobile phone application was launched by ………",
                    "optionA": " Common Services Centers (CSC)",
                    "optionB": " National Green Tribunal",
                    "optionC": " Election Commission of India",
                    "optionD": " Supreme Court of India",
                    "Answar": " Option A",
                    "Title": "",
                    "solution": " The Common Services Centers (CSC) has recently launched the “Yogyata” mobile phone application. It aims to provide vocational education and skill enhancement opportunities to youth and other citizens in rural areas. It includes the access to courses like Cyber Security, CAD and 3D printing, to increase employability The training content is on a continuous learning mode and the courses are yearly subscription-based. ",
                    "keyString": "1",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                },
                {
                    "Question": "Which state/UT launched India’s first District Good Governance Index (DGGI)?",
                    "optionA": " Kerala",
                    "optionB": " Jammu & Kashmir",
                    "optionC": " Goa",
                    "optionD": " Sikkim",
                    "Answar": " Option B",
                    "Title": "",
                    "solution": " India’s first ever District Good Governance Index (DGGI) was released in the Union Territory of Jammu and Kashmir. In the composite ranking of the index, the Jammu district tops the list followed by districts of Doda, Samba, Pulwama and Srinagar in the UT. The Index is a framework document which assesses the performance under ten governance sectors with 58 indicators. ",
                    "keyString": "2",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                },
                {
                    "Question": "The World Bank has approved a loan of around Rs 1,000 crore for which Indian state Government?",
                    "optionA": " Odisha",
                    "optionB": " West Bengal",
                    "optionC": " Andhra Pradesh",
                    "optionD": " Karnataka",
                    "Answar": " Option B",
                    "Title": "",
                    "solution": "The World Bank has approved a loan of around Rs 1,000 crore (USA 125 million) for the West Bengal government.The loan has been approved under the ‘West Bengal Building State Capability for Inclusive Social Protection’ operation. The loan is being given for several development projects related to social security.",
                    "keyString": "3",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "date": "24th & 23th Jan 2022",
            "affairs": [
                {
                    "Question": "Which country has organised the ‘Asia Ministerial Conference on Tiger Conservation’?",
                    "optionA": " India",
                    "optionB": " Malaysia",
                    "optionC": " UK",
                    "optionD": " Sri Lanka",
                    "Answar": " Option B",
                    "solution": " Government of Malaysia and Global Tiger Forum (GTF) jointly organised the 4th Asia Ministerial Conference on Tiger Conservation.India’s Union Minister of Environment, Forest and Climate Change Bhupender Yadav delivered India’s statement at the Conference on Tiger Conservation. India will facilitate Tiger Range Countries towards finalisation of New Delhi declaration for Global Tiger Summit to be held in Russia. ",
                    "keyString": "1",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                },
                {
                    "Question": "Which country has organised the ‘Asia Ministerial Conference on Tiger Conservation’?",
                    "optionA": " India",
                    "optionB": " Malaysia",
                    "optionC": " UK",
                    "optionD": " Sri Lanka",
                    "Answar": " Option B",
                    "solution": " Government of Malaysia and Global Tiger Forum (GTF) jointly organised the 4th Asia Ministerial Conference on Tiger Conservation.India’s Union Minister of Environment, Forest and Climate Change Bhupender Yadav delivered India’s statement at the Conference on Tiger Conservation. India will facilitate Tiger Range Countries towards finalisation of New Delhi declaration for Global Tiger Summit to be held in Russia. ",
                    "keyString": "1",
                    "isBookMark": 0,
                    "isShown": 0,
                    "isCon": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}